[
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "Environmental Studies is the study of human activities only.",
      "answer": false
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "Pollution is a major concern addressed in Environmental Studies.",
      "answer": true
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "Deforestation leads to an increase in biodiversity.",
      "answer": false
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "Sustainable development aims to balance economic growth with environmental protection.",
      "answer": true
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "Climate change has no impact on sea levels.",
      "answer": false
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "Recycling helps in reducing waste and conserving natural resources.",
      "answer": true
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "Using solar energy is an example of sustainable development.",
      "answer": true
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "Cutting down forests has no effect on oxygen levels.",
      "answer": false
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "Air pollution is caused only by factories.",
      "answer": false
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "Water pollution affects marine life negatively.",
      "answer": true
    }
]
  